<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:06:58</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113761</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:06:58 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Do Temporary-Help Jobs Improve Labor Market Outcomes for Low-Skilled Workers? Evidence from "Work First"</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>David H. Autor</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Susan N. Houseman</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113761</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113761V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Temporary-help jobs offer rapid entry into paid employment, but they are typically brief and it is unknown whether they foster longer term
employment. We utilize the unique structure of Detroit's welfare-to-
work program to identify the effect of temporary-help jobs on labor market advancement. Exploiting the rotational assignment of welfare clients to numerous nonprofit contractors with differing job placement rates, we find that temporary-help job placements do
not improve and may diminish subsequent earnings and employment outcomes among participants. In contrast, job placements with direct-hire employers substantially raise earnings and employment over a seven quarter follow-up period. (JEL J22, J23, J24, J31, J68)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>J22 Time Allocation and Labor Supply</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J23 Labor Demand</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J24 Human Capital; Skills; Occupational Choice; Labor Productivity</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J31 Wage Level and Structure; Wage Differentials</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J68 Mobility, Unemployment, and Vacancies: Public Policy</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
