<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:03:43</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113740</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:03:44 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Externalities in the Classroom: How Children Exposed to Domestic Violence Affect Everyone's Kids</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Scott E. Carrell</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Mark L. Hoekstra</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113740</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113740V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>There is a widespread perception that externalities from troubled
children are significant, though measuring them is difficult due
to data and methodological limitations. We estimate the negative
spillovers caused by children from troubled families by exploiting
a unique dataset in which children's school records are matched to
domestic violence cases. We find that children from troubled families
significantly decrease the reading and math test scores of their peers
and increase misbehavior in the classroom. The achievement spillovers
are robust to within-family differences and when controlling
for school-by-year effects, providing strong evidence that neither
selection nor common shocks are driving the results. (JEL D62, I21,
J12, J13, K42)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D62 Externalities</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I21 Analysis of Education</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J12 Marriage; Marital Dissolution; Family Structure; Domestic Abuse</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J13 Fertility; Family Planning; Child Care; Children; Youth</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>K42 Illegal Behavior and the Enforcement of Law</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
