<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:15:16</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113829</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:15:17 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Sweetening the Deal? Political Connections and Sugar Mills in India</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Sandip Sukhtankar</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113829</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113829V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Political control of firms is prevalent across the world. Evidence suggests that firms profit from political connections, and politicians derive benefit from control over firms. This paper investigates an alternative mechanism through which politicians may benefit electorally from connected firms, examining sugar mills in India. I find evidence of embezzlement in politically controlled mills during election years, reflected in lower prices paid to farmers for cane. This result complements the literature on political cycles by demonstrating how
campaign funds are raised rather than used. Politicians may recompense farmers upon getting elected, possibly explaining how they can get away with pilferage. (JEL D72, G34, L66, O13, O17, Q12, Q13)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D72 Political Processes: Rent-seeking, Lobbying, Elections, Legislatures, and Voting Behavior</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>G34 Mergers; Acquisitions; Restructuring; Voting; Proxy Contests; Corporate Governance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>L66 Food; Beverages; Cosmetics; Tobacco; Wine and Spirits</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O13 Economic Development: Agriculture; Natural Resources; Energy; Environment; Other Primary Products</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O17 Formal and Informal Sectors; Shadow Economy; Institutional Arrangements</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q12 Micro Analysis of Farm Firms, Farm Households, and Farm Input Markets</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q13 Agricultural Markets and Marketing; Cooperatives; Agribusiness</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
