<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:16:33</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>115107</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:16:34 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Data and Code for: Criminal Deterrence when there are Offsetting Risks: Traffic Cameras, Vehicular Accidents, and Public Safety</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Justin Gallagher</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Paul Fisher</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>115107</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E115107V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Numerous cities have enacted electronic monitoring programs at traffic
intersections in an effort to reduce the high number of vehicle accidents.
The rationale is that the higher expected fines for running a red light will
induce drivers to stop and lead to fewer cross-road collisions. However,
the cameras also incentivize drivers to accept a greater accident risk
from stopping. We evaluate the termination of a monitoring program
via a voter referendum using 12 years of geocoded police accident data.
We find that the cameras changed the composition of accidents, but no
evidence of a reduction in total accidents or injuries.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Traffic accidents</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>red light cameras</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>H27 Taxation, Subsidies, and Revenues: Other Sources of Revenue</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>H71 State and Local Taxation, Subsidies, and Revenue</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>K32 Energy, Environmental, Health, and Safety Law</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>R28 Urban, Rural, Regional, Real Estate, and Transportation Economics: Government Policy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>R41 Transportation: Demand, Supply, and Congestion; Travel Time; Safety and Accidents; Transportation Noise</dc:subject>
                    <dc:coverage>Texas, USA</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>2003 – 2014</dc:coverage>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
