<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:10:40</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>112787</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:10:40 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Dynamics of Demand for Index Insurance: Evidence from a Long-Run Field Experiment</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Shawn Cole</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Daniel Stein</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Jeremy Tobacman</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>112787</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E112787V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>This paper estimates how experimentally-manipulated experiences with a novel financial product, rainfall index insurance, affect subsequent insurance demand. Using a seven-year panel, we develop three main findings. First, recent experience matters for demand, consistent with overinference from small samples. Second, spillovers also matter, in the sense that the recent payout experience of village co-residents affects insurance demand about as much as one's own recent payout experience. Third, the spillover effect decays as time passes while the effect of one's own experience does not. We discuss implications of this analysis for commercial sustainability of this complicated but promising risk management technology.</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>C93 Field Experiments</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>G22 Insurance; Insurance Companies; Actuarial Studies</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O13 Economic Development: Agriculture; Natural Resources; Energy; Environment; Other Primary Products</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O16 Economic Development: Financial Markets; Saving and Capital Investment; Corporate Finance and Governance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q11 Agriculture: Aggregate Supply and Demand Analysis; Prices</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q14 Agricultural Finance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q54 Climate; Natural Disasters and Their Management; Global Warming</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
