<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:06:44</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113757</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:06:44 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Information, Direct Access to Farmers, and Rural Market Performance in Central India</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Aparajita Goyal</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113757</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113757V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>This paper estimates the impact of a change in procurement strategy of a private buyer in the central Indian state of Madhya Pradesh. Beginning in October 2000, Internet kiosks and warehouses were established that provide wholesale price information
and an alternative marketing channel to soy farmers in the state. Using a new market-level dataset, the estimates suggest a significant increase in soy price after the introduction of kiosks, supporting the predictions of the theoretical model. Moreover, there is a robust increase in area under soy cultivation. The results point toward an
improvement in the functioning of rural agricultural markets. (JEL O13, O18, Q12, Q13)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>O13 Economic Development: Agriculture; Natural Resources; Energy; Environment; Other Primary Products</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O18 Economic Development: Urban, Rural, Regional, and Transportation Analysis; Housing; Infrastructure</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q12 Micro Analysis of Farm Firms, Farm Households, and Farm Input Markets</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q13 Agricultural Markets and Marketing; Cooperatives; Agribusiness</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
