<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:10:34</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>112786</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:10:34 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Rainfall Forecasts, Weather, and Wages over the Agricultural Production Cycle</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Mark R. Rosenzweig</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Christopher Udry</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>112786</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E112786V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>We look at the effects of rainfall forecasts and realized rainfall on equilibrium agricultural wages over the course of the agricultural production cycle. We show theoretically that a forecast of good weather can lower wages in the planting stage, by lowering ex ante out-migration, and can exacerbate the negative impact of adverse weather on harvest-stage wages. Using Indian household panel data describing early-season migration and district-level planting- and harvest-stage wages over the period 2005–2010, we find results consistent with the model, indicating that rainfall forecasts improve labor allocations on average but exacerbate wage volatility because they are imperfect.</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>J31 Wage Level and Structure; Wage Differentials</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J43 Agricultural Labor Markets</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O13 Economic Development: Agriculture; Natural Resources; Energy; Environment; Other Primary Products</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q11 Agriculture: Aggregate Supply and Demand Analysis; Prices</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q12 Micro Analysis of Farm Firms, Farm Households, and Farm Input Markets</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q54 Climate; Natural Disasters and Their Management; Global Warming</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
