<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:13:40</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>114579</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:13:41 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Turning a Shove into a Nudge? A "Labeled Cash Transfer" for Education</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Najy Benhassine</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Florencia Devoto</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Esther Duflo</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Pascaline Dupas</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Victor Pouliquen</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>114579</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E114579V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Conditional Cash Transfers (CCTs) have been shown to increase human capital investments, but their standard features make them expensive. We use a large randomized experiment in Morocco to estimate an alternative government-run program, a "labeled cash transfer" (LCT): a small cash transfer made to fathers of school-aged children in poor rural communities, not conditional on school attendance but explicitly labeled as an education support program. We document large gains in school participation. Adding conditionality and targeting mothers made almost no difference in our context. The program increased parents' belief that education was a worthwhile investment, a likely pathway for the results. (JEL H23, I24, 128, I38, J24, O15, O18)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>H23 Taxation and Subsidies: Externalities; Redistributive Effects; Environmental Taxes and Subsidies</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I24 Education and Inequality</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I28 Education: Government Policy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I38 Welfare, Well-Being, and Poverty: Government Programs; Provision and Effects of Welfare Programs</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J24 Human Capital; Skills; Occupational Choice; Labor Productivity</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O15 Economic Development: Human Resources; Human Development; Income Distribution; Migration</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O18 Economic Development: Urban, Rural, Regional, and Transportation Analysis; Housing; Infrastructure</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
