<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:06:53</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113760</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:06:53 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Microfinance Games</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Xavier Giné</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Pamela Jakiela</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Dean Karlan</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Jonathan Morduch</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113760</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113760V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Microfinance banks use group-based lending contracts to strengthen borrowers' incentives for diligence, but the contracts are vulnerable to free-riding and collusion. We systematically unpack microfinance
mechanisms through ten experimental games played in an experimental
economics laboratory in urban Peru. Risk-taking broadly conforms to theoretical predictions, with dynamic incentives strongly reducing risk-taking even without group-based mechanisms. Group lending increases risk-taking, especially for risk-averse borrowers, but this is moderated when borrowers form their own groups. Group
contracts benefit borrowers by creating implicit insurance against investment losses, but the costs are borne by other borrowers, especially the most risk averse. (JEL D82, G21, G31, O16)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D82 Asymmetric and Private Information; Mechanism Design</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>G21 Banks; Depository Institutions; Micro Finance Institutions; Mortgages</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>G31 Capital Budgeting; Fixed Investment and Inventory Studies; Capacity</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O16 Economic Development: Financial Markets; Saving and Capital Investment; Corporate Finance and Governance</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
