<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T09:51:12</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>122886</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 09:51:13 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Data and Code for: The macroeconomic effects of oil supply news: Evidence from OPEC announcements</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Diego R. Känzig</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>122886</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E122886V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>This repository contains the replication files for “The macroeconomic effects of oil supply news: Evidence from OPEC announcements”. The files are stored in the following folders:codesdatainstrumentresultsFor detailed information on the data used as well as instructions on how to use the replication codes, see the README pdf file.The main results of the project can be summarized as follows:This paper studies how changes in oil supply expectations affect the oil price and the macroeconomy. Using a novel identification design, exploiting institutional features of OPEC and high-frequency data, I identify an oil supply news shock. These shocks have statistically and economically significant effects. Negative news leads to an immediate increase in oil prices, a gradual fall in oil production and an increase in inventories. This has consequences for the U.S. economy: activity falls, prices and inflation expectations rise, and the dollar depreciates - providing evidence for a strong channel operating through supply expectations.</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>business cycles</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>oil supply</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>news shocks</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>external instruments</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>high-frequency identification</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>OPEC announcements</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>C32 Multiple or Simultaneous Equation Models: Time-Series Models; Dynamic Quantile Regressions; Dynamic Treatment Effect Models; Diffusion Processes; State Space Models</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>E31 Price Level; Inflation; Deflation</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>E32 Business Fluctuations; Cycles</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q43 Energy and the Macroeconomy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:coverage>United States</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>1/1974 – 12/2017</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:type>aggregate data</dc:type>
                    <dc:source>Macroeconomic and financial data retrieved via FRED, Datastream, and the IFS. Please see the README file for detailed data references.&lt;br&gt;</dc:source>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
