<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:04:53</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113966</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:04:54 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Power Laws in Economics: An Introduction</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Xavier Gabaix</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113966</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113966V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Many of the insights of economics seem to be qualitative, with many fewer reliable quantitative laws. However a series of power laws in economics do count as true and nontrivial quantitative laws—and they are not only established empirically, but also understood theoretically. I will start by providing several illustrations of empirical power laws having to do with patterns involving cities, firms, and the stock market. I summarize some of the theoretical explanations that have been proposed. I suggest that power laws help us explain many economic phenomena, including aggregate economic fluctuations. I hope to clarify why power laws are so special, and to demonstrate their utility. In conclusion, I list some power-law-related economic enigmas that demand further exploration.</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D01 Microeconomic Behavior: Underlying Principles</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>R11 Regional Economic Activity: Growth, Development, Environmental Issues, and Changes</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>L11 Production, Pricing, and Market Structure; Size Distribution of Firms</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
