<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T09:51:58</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>127541</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 09:51:59 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Data and Code for: Risk-based Selection in Unemployment Insurance: Evidence and Implications</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Camille Landais</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Arash  Nekoei</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Peter Nilsson</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>David Seim</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Johannes Spinnewijn</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>127541</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E127541V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>
			
				
					This paper studies whether adverse selection can rationalize a universal mandate for unemployment insurance (UI). Building on a unique feature of the unemployment policy in Sweden,
where workers can opt for supplemental UI coverage above a minimum mandate, we provide the
first direct evidence for adverse selection in UI and derive its implications for UI design. We
find that the unemployment risk is more than twice as high for workers who buy supplemental
coverage. Exploiting variation in risk and prices, we show how 25-30% of this correlation is
driven by risk-based selection, with the remainder driven by moral hazard. Due to the moral
hazard and despite the adverse selection we find that mandating the supplemental coverage to
individuals with low willingness-to-pay would be sub-optimal. We show under which conditions
a design leaving choice to workers would dominate a UI system with a single mandate. In this
design, using a subsidy for supplemental coverage is optimal and complementary to the use of
a minimum mandate.

				
			
		</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Adverve Selection</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>unemployment insurance</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Mandate</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Subsidy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>D82 Asymmetric and Private Information; Mechanism Design</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>E24 Employment; Unemployment; Wages; Intergenerational Income Distribution; Aggregate Human Capital; Aggregate Labor Productivity</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J64 Unemployment: Models, Duration, Incidence, and Job Search</dc:subject>
                    <dc:coverage>Sweden</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>2002 – 2009</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>1990 – 2015</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>2002 – 2012</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>1985 – 2015</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:type>program source code</dc:type>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
