<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T09:51:49</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>120570</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 09:51:52 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Data and Code for: The Legacy of Colonial Medicine in Central Africa</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Sara Lowes</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Eduardo Montero</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>120570</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E120570V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Between 1921 and 1956, French colonial governments organized medical campaigns to treat and prevent sleeping sickness. Villagers were forcibly examined and injected with medications with severe, sometimes fatal, side effects. We digitized thirty years of archival records to document the locations of campaign visits at a granular geographic level for five central African countries. We find that greater campaign exposure reduces vaccination rates and trust in medicine -- as measured by willingness to consent to a blood test. We examine relevance for present day health initiatives;&amp;nbsp; World Bank projects in the health sector are less successful in areas with greater exposure.&amp;nbsp;</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>Trust</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Medicine</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>colonialism</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>health</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>vaccinations</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>culture</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I15 Health and Economic Development</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I18 Health: Government Policy; Regulation; Public Health</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>N37 Economic History: Labor and Consumers, Demography, Education, Health, Welfare, Income, Wealth, Religion, and Philanthropy: Africa; Oceania</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O55 Economywide Country Studies: Africa</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Z10 Cultural Economics; Economic Sociology; Economic Anthropology: General</dc:subject>
                    <dc:coverage>Central Africa</dc:coverage>
                    <dc:coverage>1921 – 2018</dc:coverage>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
