<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:03:33</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113738</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:03:34 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Age at Arrival, English Proficiency, and Social Assimilation among US Immigrants</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Hoyt Bleakley</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Aimee Chin</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113738</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113738V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Are the English proficiency and social outcomes of US immigrants
the result of their cultural preferences or of more fundamental constraints?
Using 2000 census microdata, we relate the English proficiency,
marriage, fertility, and residential location variables of
immigrants to their age at the time of arrival in the United States,
and, in particular, whether that age fell within the "critical period"
of language acquisition. We interpret the differences between
younger and older arrivers as effects of English language skills and
construct an instrumental variable for English language skills. Two-stage-least-squares estimates suggest English proficiency increases
the likelihood of divorce and intermarriage. It decreases fertility
and, for some, ethnic
enclave residence. (JEL J11, J13, J61, R23, Z13)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>J11 Demographic Trends, Macroeconomic Effects, and Forecasts</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J13 Fertility; Family Planning; Child Care; Children; Youth</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J61 Geographic Labor Mobility; Immigrant Workers</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>R23 Urban, Rural, Regional, Real Estate, and Transportation Economics: Regional Migration; Regional Labor Markets; Population; Neighborhood Characteristics</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Z13 Economic Sociology; Economic Anthropology; Language; Social and Economic Stratification</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
