<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:13:59</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>114594</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:13:59 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Asymmetric Incentives in Subsidies: Evidence from a Large-Scale Electricity Rebate Program</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Koichiro Ito</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>114594</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E114594V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>Many countries use substantial public funds to subsidize reductions in negative externalities. Such policy designs create asymmetric incentives because increases in externalities remain unpriced. I investigate the implications of such policies by using a regression discontinuity design in California's electricity rebate program. Using household-level panel data, I find that the incentive produced precisely estimated zero treatment effects on energy conservation in coastal areas. In contrast, the rebate induced short-run and long-run consumption reductions in inland areas. Income, climate, and air conditioner saturation significantly drive the heterogeneity. Finally, I provide a cost-effectiveness analysis and investigate how to improve the policy design. (JEL D12, D62, H76, L94, L98, Q48)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D12 Consumer Economics: Empirical Analysis</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>D62 Externalities</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>H76 State and Local Government: Other Expenditure Categories</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>L94 Electric Utilities</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>L98 Industry Studies: Utilities and Transportation: Government Policy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Q48 Energy: Government Policy</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
