<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:05:12</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113840</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:05:13 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Can Mobile Phones Improve Learning? Evidence from a Field Experiment in Niger</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Jenny C. Aker</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Christopher Ksoll</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Travis J. Lybbert</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113840</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113840V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>The returns to educational investments hinge on whether such investments can improve the quality and persistence of educational gains. We report the results from a randomized evaluation of an adult education program in Niger, in which some students learned how to use simple mobile phones (Project ABC). Students in ABC villages achieved test scores that were 0.19-0.26 standard deviations higher than those in standard adult education classes, and standardized math test scores remained higher seven months after the end of classes. These results suggest that simple information technology can be harnessed to improve educational outcomes among rural populations. (JEL D83, I21, O15, O33)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D83 Search; Learning; Information and Knowledge; Communication; Belief; Unawareness</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I21 Analysis of Education</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O15 Economic Development: Human Resources; Human Development; Income Distribution; Migration</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O33 Technological Change: Choices and Consequences; Diffusion Processes</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
