<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:06:35</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>113681</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:06:36 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Ethnolinguistic Favoritism in African Politics</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Andrew Dickens</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>113681</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E113681V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>African political leaders have a tendency to favor members of their own ethnic group. Yet for all other ethnic groups in a country, it is unclear whether having a similar ethnicity to the leader is beneficial. To shed light on this issue, I use a continuous measure of linguistic similarity to quantify the ethnic similarity of a leader to all ethnic groups in a country. Combined with panel data on 163 ethnic groups partitioned across 35 sub-Saharan countries, I use within-group time variation in similarity that results from a partitioned group's concurrent exposure to multiple national leaders. 
Findings show that ethnic favoritism is more widespread than previously believed: in addition to evidence of coethnic favoritism, I document evidence of non-coethnic favoritism that typically goes undetected in the absence of a continuous measure of similarity. I also find that patronage tends to be targeted toward ethnic regions rather than individuals of a particular ethnic group. I relate these results to the literature on coalition building, and provide evidence that ethnicity is one of the guiding principles behind high-level government appointments.</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>D72 Political Processes: Rent-seeking, Lobbying, Elections, Legislatures, and Voting Behavior</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J15 Economics of Minorities, Races, Indigenous Peoples, and Immigrants; Non-labor Discrimination</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O15 Economic Development: Human Resources; Human Development; Income Distribution; Migration</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>O17 Formal and Informal Sectors; Shadow Economy; Institutional Arrangements</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>Z13 Economic Sociology; Economic Anthropology; Language; Social and Economic Stratification</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
