<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<oaipmHtype xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlnsterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <responseDate>2021-04-14T10:14:08</responseDate>
    <request verb="GetRecord" set="https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/ICPSR/oai/studies"/>
    <GetRecord>
        <record>
            <header>
                <identifier>114555</identifier>
                <datestamp>Wed Apr 14 10:14:08 EDT 2021</datestamp>
            </header>
            <metadata>
                <dc:oaiDcType>
                    <dc:title>Replication data for: Did the Americanization Movement Succeed? An Evaluation of the Effect of English-Only and Compulsory Schooling Laws on Immigrants</dc:title>
                    <dc:creator>Adriana Lleras-Muney</dc:creator>
                    <dc:creator>Allison Shertzer</dc:creator>
                    <dc:identifier>114555</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:identifier>https://doi.org/10.3886/E114555V1</dc:identifier>
                    <dc:description>We provide the first estimates of the effect of statutes requiring English as the language of instruction and compulsory schooling laws on the school enrollment, work, literacy, and English fluency of immigrant children during the Americanization period (1910-1930). English-only statutes moderately increased the literacy of certain foreign-born children, particularly those living in cities or whose parents were not fluent in English. However, these laws had no impact on immigrants' eventual labor market outcomes or measures of social integration (from 1940 census and WWII enlistment records). Only laws regulating the age when children could work significantly affected immigrant outcomes. (JEL I21, I26, I28, J13, J15, N31, N32)</dc:description>
                    <dc:subject>I21 Analysis of Education</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I26 Returns to Education</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>I28 Education: Government Policy</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J13 Fertility; Family Planning; Child Care; Children; Youth</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>J15 Economics of Minorities, Races, Indigenous Peoples, and Immigrants; Non-labor Discrimination</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>N31 Economic History: Labor and Consumers, Demography, Education, Health, Welfare, Income, Wealth, Religion, and Philanthropy: U.S.; Canada: Pre-1913</dc:subject>
                    <dc:subject>N32 Economic History: Labor and Consumers, Demography, Education, Health, Welfare, Income, Wealth, Religion, and Philanthropy: U.S.; Canada: 1913-</dc:subject>
                </dc:oaiDcType>
            </metadata>
        </record>
    </GetRecord>
</oaipmHtype>
